漫威影业
宇宙魔方已经苏醒
The Tesseract has awakened.
它在一个渺小的世界  人类的世界
It is on a little world, a human world.
人类想要使用它的力量
They would wield its power,
但只有我们的盟友了解它
but our ally knows its workings
人类是痴心妄想
as they never will.
他已经做好准备
He is ready to lead
率领我们的齐塔瑞大军
and our force, our Chitauri, will follow.
他将成为地球的主宰
A world will be his.
而你将统治整个宇宙
The universe, yours.
至于人类  只能乖乖接受毁灭的命运
And the humans, what can they do but burn?
全体人员注意  撤离命令已确认
All personnel, the evacuation order has been confirmed.
联合暗能行动  西分部
飞马计划
太空总署空间辐射中心
神盾局加速器测试中心
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
问题就在这里  长官  我们不知道
That's the problem, sir. We don't know.
塞尔维格博士4小时前检测到
Dr Selvig read an energy surge
宇宙魔方释放出了一股能量涌
from the Tesseract four hours ago.
太空总署没有允许塞尔维格进行测试
NASA didn't authorise Selvig to go to test phase.
他没做测试  他当时根本不在
He wasn't testing it. He wasn't even in the room.
能量是自然触发
Spontaneous event.
它就自行启动了吗
It just turned itself on?
现在达到什么能量等级了
Where are the energy levels now?
还在上升  塞尔维格关不掉它
Climbing. When Selvig couldn't shut it down,
我们只好下令撤离
we ordered evac.
全员撤离还要多久
How long to get everyone out?
园区应能在半小时内清空
Campus should be clear in the next half-hour.
再快点
Do better.
长官  撤离可能也没有用
Sir, evacuation may be futile.
那我们该让大家回去睡觉吗
We should tell them to go back to sleep?
如果我们无法控制宇宙魔方的能量
If we can't control the Tesseract's energy,
危害波及范围或许会超出我们的想象
there may not be a minimum safe distance.
我要你去确认转移
I need you to make sure
二阶的所有原型机
the Phase 2 prototypes are shipped out.
长官  现在真的还要顾及那个吗
Sir, is that really a priority right now?
只要地球末日还没来临
Until such time as the world ends,
我们就还要做好充足的准备
we will act as though it intends to spin on.
清空地下的所有技术设备
Clear out the tech below.
把二阶的所有设备装车运走
Every piece of Phase 2 on a truck and gone.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
跟我来
With me.
博士  什么情况
Talk to me, Doctor.
局长
Director.
现在我们有确认的情况吗
Is there anything we know for certain?
宇宙魔方乱动起来了
The Tesseract is misbehaving.
-你在说笑吗  -这一点也不好笑
- Is that supposed to be funny? - No, it's not funny at all.
宇宙魔方不止被激活了  她还  自作主张
The Tesseract is not only active, she's behaving.
你试过切断电源了吧
I assume you pulled the plug.
她自身就是能量源
She's an energy source.
我们关上电源  她能重新启动
We turn off the power, she turns it back on.
如果她的能量达到峰值
If she reaches peak level...
我们为此做了准备  博士
We prepared for this, Doctor.
利用来自宇宙的能量
Harnessing energy from space.
我们还没有掌控的能力
But we don't have the harness.
我的计算还远没有完成
My calculations are far from complete.
而现在她在释放干扰和辐射
And she's throwing off interference, radiation.
没什么危害  只是低水平的伽马射线
Nothing harmful, low levels of gamma radiation.
那是能有危害的
That can be harmful.
巴顿特工呢
Where's Agent Barton?
那只鹰吗
The Hawk?
当然还是窝在巢里了
Up in his nest, as usual.
巴顿特工  回话
Agent Barton, report.
我让你负责安保
I gave you this detail
是让你密切关注一切情况
so you could keep a close eye on things.
我在高处看得更清楚
Well, I see better from a distance.
那你看到是什么激活了魔方吗
Have you seen anything that might set this thing off?
博士  能量又激增了
Doctor, it's spiking again.
没有人进出
No one's come or gone.
塞尔维格没问题
And Selvig's clean.
没与人接触或传递信息
No contacts, no IMs.
如果有谁在搞鬼  长官
If there was any tampering, sir,
也不是我们这边的人
it wasn't at this end.
什么意思
"At this end"?
魔方是通向宇宙另一端的门吧
Yeah, the Cube is a doorway to the other end of space, right?
而门从两边都能开
Doors open from both sides.
还没到
Not yet.
先生  请放下你的矛
Sir, please put down the spear.
你挺勇敢[有心]
You have heart.
劝你不要
Please don't.
我还需要它
I still need that.
没必要把事情闹得更大
This doesn't have to get any messier.
当然有必要
Of course it does.
我远道而来就是为了它
I've come too far for anything else.
我是洛基  来自阿斯加德
I am Loki, of Asgard
我肩负着光荣的使命
and I am burdened with glorious purpose.
洛基
Loki,
托尔的弟弟
brother of Thor.
我们跟你们毫无纠葛
We have no quarrel with your people.
就像蚂蚁也没有招惹靴子
An ant has no quarrel with a boot.
你的意思是要踩死我们吗
Are you planning to step on us?
我带来了福音
I come with glad tidings
我要帮你们摆脱束缚
of a world made free.
什么的束缚
Free from what?
自由
Freedom.
自由是人生最大的谎言
Freedom is life's great lie.
如果你能发自内心接受这一点
Once you accept that, in your heart,
那你就能获得安宁
you will know peace.
你口口声声说安宁
Yeah, you say "Peace,"
但我觉得你的意思正相反
I kind of think you mean the other thing.
长官  弗瑞局长在拖延时间
Sir, Director Fury is stalling.
这个地方就要爆炸了
This place is about to blow
我们会被压在几十米的石头下
and drop a hundred feet of rock on us.
他想要埋葬我们
He means to bury us.
就像古时的法老
Like the pharaohs of old.
他说得对  传送门正在自我塌陷
He's right. The portal is collapsing in on itself.
再过两分钟就会达到极值
We've got maybe two minutes before this goes critical.
那好吧
Well, then.
我要用这些车
I need these vehicles.
-那是谁  -不知道
- Who's that? - They didn't tell me.
希尔
Hill!
听得到吗
Do you copy?
巴顿叛变了
Barton has turned.
他们抢走了宇宙魔方  拦住他们
They have the Tesseract! Shut them down!
好了  走吧  别管了  快走
Okay, let's go. No, leave it. Go!
楼上撤空了  长官  你得赶快离开
We're clear upstairs, sir. You need to go.
局长
Director?
弗瑞局长  听到了吗
Director Fury, do you copy?
宇宙魔方被敌人抢走了
The Tesseract is with a hostile force.
有人负伤  希尔你呢
I have men down. Hill?
还有很多人被埋在地下
A lot of men still under.
我不知道有多少幸存者
I don't know how many survivors.
发出全面命令
Sound a general call.
所有不参与救援的人员
I want every living soul not working rescue
去追查箱子的下落
looking for that briefcase.
明白
Roger that.
科尔森  返回基地  这是7级事件
Coulson, get back to base. This is a Level Seven.
现在
As of right now,
战争已经打响
we are at war.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
复仇者联盟
今晚和我想的不太一样
我知道你是怎么想的
相信我
这样更好
你为谁卖命
是勒曼托夫吗
他觉得
我们还需要经过他同意
才能运我们的货吗
不是索罗霍布将军负责出口生意吗
索罗霍布
他就是个中间人  幌子
你那过时的情报害了你
赫赫有名的黑寡妇
也不过是个花瓶而已
你真的觉得我漂亮吗
告诉勒曼托夫  不劳他运坦克了
告诉他  他玩完了
不过
你可能得写下来了
...you may have to write it down.
找她的
你给我听好了
你在114号索伦斯基广场三楼
You're at 1-14 Silensky Plaza, 3rd floor.
我们的F22战斗机距你只有8英里
We have an F-22 exactly eight miles out.
让那女人接电话  否则不等你跑到大厅
Put the woman on the phone, or I will blow up the block
我就能炸平整条街
before you can make the lobby.
-你得回来  -你开玩笑吗  我在工作
- We need you to come in. - Are you kidding? I'm working.
这事更紧急
This takes precedence.
我正在进行审讯
I'm in the middle of an interrogation.
而这个傻逼什么都说了
This moron is giving me everything.
我没什么都说啊
I don't give everything.
听着  我现在脱不开身
Look, you can't pull me out of this right now.
娜塔莎
Natasha...
巴顿被策反了
Barton's been compromised.
你先别挂
Let me put you on hold.
巴顿现在在哪里
Where is Barton now?
-不知道  -他还活着吧
- We don't know. - But he's alive?
应该是的  等你回来再细说
We think so. I'll brief you on everything when you get back.
但你得先去找大家伙谈谈
But first, we need you to talk to the big guy.
科尔森  你也知道斯塔克
Coulson, you know that Stark
并不怎么信任我
trusts me about as far as he can throw me.
斯塔克交给我  你去找那个"大家伙"
I've got Stark. You get the big guy.
你是谁
快出去
这里有病人
你是医生
You're a doctor.
我爸爸昏迷不醒
他发烧了  还一直难受地呻吟
但眼睛却睁不开
慢慢说
我爸爸
像他们一样吗
求你了
Please.
该先收钱的  班纳
You should've got paid up front, Banner.
对于一个该远离压力的人来说
You know, for a man who's supposed to be avoiding stress
你可真是选了一个好地方安居
you picked a hell of a place to settle.
远离压力不是我的诀窍
Avoiding stress isn't the secret.
那是什么  做瑜伽吗
Then what is it? Yoga?
你把我引到郊区来  真聪明
You brought me to the edge of the city. Smart.
这里肯定被包围了吧
I assume the whole place is surrounded.
只有你和我
Just you and me.
你那个小演员呢
And your actress buddy?
她也是间谍吗  入行还真早啊
Is she a spy, too? They start that young?
我当年就是
I did.
你是谁
Who are you?
娜塔莎·罗曼诺夫
Natasha Romanoff.
你是来杀我的吗  罗曼诺夫女士
Are you here to kill me, Ms Romanoff?
因为那对所有人都不会有好结果的
Because that's not going to work out for everyone.
不  当然不是  我是代表神盾局而来
No, of course not. I'm here on behalf of S.H.I.E.L.D.
神盾局
S.H.I.E.L.D.
他们怎么找到我的
How did they find me?
我们一直掌握着你的行踪  博士
We never lost you, Doctor.
只是一直保持着距离
We've kept our distance.
甚至还替你甩掉了一些其他相关方
Even helped keep some other interested parties off your scent.
为什么
Why?
尼克·弗瑞还挺信任你
Nick Fury seems to trust you.
但现在你得跟我走
But now we need you to come in.
要是我不肯呢
What if I say no?
我会说服你
I'll persuade you.
要是...那个家伙不肯呢
And what if the other guy says no?
你一年多没出过"事故"了
You've been more than a year without an incident.
我想你应该也不想破这个戒
I don't think you want to break that streak.
我并不是总能如愿的
Well, I don't every time get what I want.
博士  我们可能要迎来一场全球灾难
Doctor, we're facing a potential global catastrophe.
那是我一直在努力避免的
Well, those I actively try to avoid.
这个
This
是宇宙魔方
is the Tesseract.
它有毁灭整个地球的能量
It has the potential energy to wipe out the planet.
那弗瑞想要我做什么  把它吃掉吗
What does Fury want me to do, swallow it?
他要你找到它  它被抢走了
He wants you to find it. It's been taken.
它发出的伽马信号太弱  我们无法追踪
It emits a gamma signature that's too weak for us to trace.
而你是最了解伽马射线的人了
There's no one that knows gamma radiation like you do.
否则我也不会来找你
If there was, that's where I'd be.
所以  弗瑞不是派你来抓怪物的咯
So, Fury isn't after the monster?
反正他不是这么跟我说的
Not that he's told me.
他什么都会跟你说吗
And he tells you everything?
去跟弗瑞谈吧  他需要你的帮助
Talk to Fury. He needs you on this.
他要把我关起来吗
He needs me in a cage?
没有人会把你关起...
No one's going to put you in a...
不要再骗我了
Stop lying to me!
抱歉  我不该这么凶
I'm sorry. That was mean.
我就是想试探一下你
I just wanted to see what you'd do.
这样吧  我们好好说话
Why don't we do this the easy way
你把枪收起来
where you don't use that
而我也确保那个家伙不会乱来
and the other guy doesn't make a mess.
好吗
Okay?
娜塔莎
Natasha?
退后
Stand down.
一切正常
We're good here.
还说"只有你和我"呢
"Just you and me."
这太过分了  局长
This is out of line, Director.
你在摆弄你控制不了的力量
You're dealing with forces you can't control.
你打过仗吗  理事先生  上过战场吗
You ever been in a war, Councilman? In a firefight?
你那时觉得能完全掌控局面吗
Did you feel an overabundance of control?
你是说这个阿斯加德已经向地球宣战了吗
You're saying that this Asgard is declaring war on our planet?
不是阿斯加德  只是洛基
Not Asgard. Loki.
他不可能是单干  另一个神呢
He can't be working alone. What about the other one?
他哥哥
His brother.
根据我们的情报  托尔不是敌人
Our intelligence says Thor is not a hostile
但他离我们太远了
but he's worlds away.
我们不能指望他来帮忙
We can't depend on him to help, either.
我们只能靠自己
It's up to us.
所以你更应该全力开发二阶
Which is why you should be focusing on Phase 2.
它正是为这种情况...
It was designed for exactly this...
二阶还没完成  但敌人却准备好了
Phase 2 isn't ready. Our enemy is.
我们需要一支应急小队
We need a response team.
复仇者计划已被取消
The Avengers Initiative was shut down.
我不是指复仇者联盟
This isn't about the Avengers.
我们看过那份名单
We've seen the list.
你有着世界一流的秘密特工组织
You're running the world's greatest covert security network
却要把人类的命运交给
and you're going to leave the fate of the human race
一群怪胎吗
to a handful of freaks.
我没有要把任何事交给任何人
I'm not leaving anything to anyone.
我们确实需要一支应急小队
We need a response team.
这些人或许孤僻  甚至不太正常
These people may be isolated, unbalanced even
但我相信只要有正确的动力
but I believe with the right push
他们就能成为我们需要的力量
they can be exactly what we need.
你相信吗
You believe?
靠感情可赢不了战争  局长
War isn't won by sentiment, Director.
是的  只能靠战士
No, it's won by soldiers.
没时间了
There's not enough time.
我得让飞机坠海
I got to put her in the water!
你不是一个人
You won't be alone.
天啊
Oh, my God.
这家伙还活着
This guy is still alive!
睡不着吗
Trouble sleeping?
我睡了70年  长官  我想我睡得够久了
I slept for 70 years, sir. I think I've had my fill.
那你该出去走走
Then you should be out,
庆祝一下  看看世界
celebrating, seeing the world.
我沉睡的时候  世界还在打仗
When I went under, the world was at war.
等我醒来  他们说战争打赢了
I wake up, they say we won.
却没说我们失去了什么
They didn't say what we lost.
我们一路走来犯了些错误
We've made some mistakes along the way.
有些就在不久之前
Some, very recently.
你有任务要给我吗  长官
Are you here with a mission, sir?
是的
I am.
想让我回归这个世界吗
Trying to get me back in the world?
是让你拯救世界
Trying to save it.
九头蛇的秘密武器
HYDRA's secret weapon.
宇宙魔方
是霍华德·斯塔克在找你的时候
Howard Stark fished that out of the ocean
从海底打捞上来的
when he was looking for you.
他和我们想的一样
He thought what we think.
宇宙魔方是开发无限可再生能源的关键
The Tesseract could be the key to unlimited sustainable energy.
这正是世界所迫切需要的
That's something the world sorely needs.
它被谁抢走了
Who took it from you?
他叫洛基
He's called Loki.
他不是本地人
He's not from around here.
你加入的话还有很多情况需要了解
There's a lot we'll have to bring you up to speed on if you're in.
这世界和你记忆中的比起来
The world has gotten even stranger
变得更加奇怪了
than you already know.
事到如今  我觉得已经没什么能让我意外了
At this point, I doubt anything would surprise me.
我赌10块钱  说你错了
Ten bucks says you're wrong.
任务资料
There's a debriefing packet
已经放在你公寓了
waiting for you back at your apartment.
关于宇宙魔方
Is there anything you can tell us about the Tesseract
你能告诉我们什么吗
that we ought to know now?
你们就不该把它捞上来
You should have left it in the ocean.
这边准备就绪  接下来看你的了
Good to go on this end. The rest is up to you.
你断开输电线了吗
You disconnected the transmission lines?
我们与电网断开了吗
Are we off the grid?
斯塔克大厦即将成为
Stark Tower is about to become a beacon
自给清洁能源的灯塔
of self-sustaining clean energy.
如果方舟反应堆能接替发电
Well, assuming the arc reactor takes over
并且正常运行的话
and it actually works.
应该没问题
I assume.
开灯吧
Light her up.
斯塔克
看起来怎么样
How does it look?
像圣诞彩灯  但更有我的风格
Like Christmas, but with more me.
我们得加大公众宣传
We've got to go wider on the public awareness campaign.
你得在媒体上造势
You need to do some press.
我明天去华盛顿
I'm in DC tomorrow,
为另外三座大楼选址
I'm working on the zoning for the next three buildings.
派珀  你把气氛都毁了  当下
Pepper, you're killing me. The moment, remember?
要享受当下
Enjoy the moment.
等你进来我再享受
Get in here and I will.
先生  神盾局的科尔森特工打来电话
Sir, Agent Coulson of S.H.I.E.L.D. is on the line.
说我在外面
I'm not in.
我确实在外面
I'm actually out.
先生  恐怕他坚持要找您
Sir, I'm afraid he's insisting.
强硬点  贾维斯  我有约会
Grow a spine, Jarvis. I got a date.
能量水平稳定...吧
Levels are holding steady, I think.
当然了  是我亲自动手的
Of course they are. I was directly involved.
这正好让我想到一个问题
Which brings me to my next question.
当天才的感觉如何
How does it feel to be a genius?
我怎么会知道
Well, I really wouldn't know, now would I?
这叫什么话  这一切都归功于你
What do you mean? All this came from you.
不  这一切都归功于这个
No, all this came from that.
别这么谦虚  拜托
Give yourself some credit. Please.
斯塔克大厦就是你的孩子
Stark Tower is your baby.
你有12%的功劳
Give yourself 12% of the credit.
才12%
12%?
商量一下可以升到15%
An argument can be made for 15.
我的孩子我只有12%的份
12%? My baby?
毕竟重活都是我干的
Well, I did do all the heavy lifting.
都不是比喻  重物都是我搬的
Literally, I lifted the heavy things.
而且  不好意思  安全漏洞怎么算
And, sorry, but the security snafu?
该算在你头上
That was on you.
-我的私人电梯  -你是说我们的电梯吧
- My private elevator... - You mean our elevator?
挤满了一身臭汗的工人
...it was teeming with sweaty workmen.
过会儿你会因为我说了占多少份这话
I'm going to pay for that comment about percentages
而温柔地报复我  是吧
in some subtle way later, aren't I?
没你想的那么温柔
It's not going to be that subtle.
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
我在下一栋大楼上写上你的名字
The next building is gonna say "Potts" on the tower.
直接写在地契上吧
On the lease.
打电话问问你妈  你能留下过夜吗
Call your mom. Can you bunk over?
先生  您的电话
Sir, the telephone.
恐怕我的程序被人改写了
I'm afraid my protocols are being overridden.
斯塔克  我们得谈谈
Mr Stark, we need to talk.
这里是托尼·斯塔克的生化机器人替身
You have reached the life model decoy of Tony Stark.
-有事请留言  -是急事
- Please leave a message. - This is urgent.
那就说得急一点
Then leave it urgently.
安全漏洞  你的错
Security breach. It's on you.
-斯塔克先生  -菲尔  快进来
- Mr Stark. - Phil! Come in.
菲尔
"Phil"?
我不能久留
I can't stay.
他的名字不是"特工"吗
His first name is "Agent."
进来吧  我们在庆祝
Come on in. We're celebrating.
所以他不能久留
Which is why he can't stay.
你得尽快看完这些资料
We need you to look this over as soon as possible.
我不喜欢别人递我东西
I don't like being handed things.
没事  我就喜欢别人递我东西
That's fine, because I love to be handed things.
我们换换吧
So, let's trade.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的正式咨询时间为每隔一周的周四8点到5点
Official consulting hours are between 8 and 5 every other Thursday.
这不是咨询
This isn't a consultation.
是关于复仇者联盟吗
Is this about the Avengers?
我对那个一无所知
Which I know nothing about.
复仇者计划不是被弃了吗
The Avengers Initiative was scrapped, I thought.
再说我都不够格
And I didn't even qualify.
这我也不知情
I didn't know that either.
显然人家嫌我不稳定  自我为中心
Apparently I'm volatile, self-obsessed,
没有团队精神
don't play well with others.
这我倒是知道
That I did know.
我们现在顾不上性格问题了
This isn't about personality profiles any more.
随便了  波茨小姐  能过来一下吗
Whatever. Ms Potts, got a second?
稍等
Half a mo.
我以为我们能浪漫一会呢
You know, I thought we were having a moment.
我只能享受12%的浪漫
I was having 12% of a moment.
情况好像很严重  菲尔看上去挺紧张
This seems serious. Phil's pretty shaken.
你怎么知道  你干嘛叫他菲尔
How would you know if it's... Why is he "Phil"?
这都是什么
What is all this?
这是
This is
自己看吧
this.
我今晚就飞去华盛顿
I'm going to take the jet to DC tonight.
-明天吧  -你有功课要做  很多功课
- Tomorrow. - You have homework. You have a lot of homework.
要是我没有呢
Well, what if I didn't?
-没有  -是啊
- If you didn't? - Yeah.
你是说等你做完了吗
You mean when you've finished?
那样的话
Well, then...
说定了  旅途顺利
Square deal. Fly safe.
好好用功
Work hard.
你会路过拉瓜地亚机场吗
So, any chance you're driving by LaGuardia?
-我捎你一程吧  -太好了
- I can drop you. - Fantastic.
那个大提琴手怎么样了
I want to hear about the cellist.
你们还在约会吗
Is that still a thing?
她回波特兰了
She moved back to Portland.
怎么会
What?
我们离总部还有约40分钟航程  长官
We're about 40 minutes out from home base, sir.
班纳博士企图复制我所注射的血清吗
So, this Dr Banner was trying to replicate the serum they used on me?
很多人都试过
A lot of people were.
你是世上第一个超级英雄
You were the world's first superhero.
班纳以为伽马射线可能是破解
Banner thought gamma radiation might hold the key
厄斯金原始配方的关键
to unlocking Erskine's original formula.
可惜结果不怎么好  是吧
Didn't really go his way, did it?
是啊
Not so much.
不过他正常的时候
When he's not that thing, though,
他简直就像史蒂芬·霍金
the guy's like a Stephen Hawking.
他是个聪明绝顶的人
He's like a smart person.
我必须要说
I gotta say,
我很荣幸能正式见到你
it's an honour to meet you officially.
我之前其实算是见过你
I've sort of met you. I mean,
你沉睡时我去看过你
I watched you while you were sleeping.
我是说  我们发现
I mean, I was present
被冰冻昏迷不醒的你时  我也在场
while you were unconscious from the ice.
说真的  你能加入我们
You know, it's really just a huge honour
真是莫大的荣幸
to have you on board this...
希望我能胜任
I hope I'm the man for the job.
你肯定能  毫无疑问
Oh, you are. Absolutely.
我们对你的制服做了些修改
We made some modifications to the uniform.
我还提了点设计意见
I had a little design input.
我的制服
The uniform?
星条的样式不会...
Aren't the stars and stripes a little
太过时了吗
old-fashioned?
考虑到眼下的局势
With everything that's happening
和即将到来的恶战
and the things that are about to come to light,
人们或许正需要点过去的精神
people might just need a little old-fashioned.
齐塔瑞人越来越耐不住了
The Chitauri grow restless.
叫他们控制好自己
Let them gird themselves.
我会率领他们发动一场光辉的战役
I will lead them in the glorious battle.
战役
Battle?
捏死地球上的虫子也叫战役吗
Against the meagre might of Earth?
光辉而轻松的战役
Glorious, not lengthy.
前提是你的大军真如你说的那样所向披靡
If your force is as formidable as you claim.
你竟敢质疑我们
You question us?
质疑他
You question him,
别忘了是他把权杖交给了你
he who put the sceptre in your hand?
传授你远古的真知  给予你新的使命
Who gave you ancient knowledge and new purpose
在你被流放和挫败的时候
when you were cast out, defeated?
我曾是王
I was a king!
阿斯加德的合法国王
The rightful king of Asgard,
却被背叛
betrayed.
你的志向  渺小
Your ambition is little
而幼稚
and born of childish need.
我们要的不止是地球
We look beyond the Earth
宇宙魔方会开启更广博的世界
to the greater worlds the Tesseract will unveil.
宇宙魔方还在我这里呢
You don't have the Tesseract yet.
我没有威胁你的意思
I don't threaten.
但只要传送门尚未打开
But until I open the doors,
你的军队还非由我统领
until your force is mine to command,
你也只是空谈
you are but words.
你去发动战争吧  阿斯加德人
You will have your war, Asgardian.
可如果你失败了
If you fail,
如果宇宙魔方落入他人之手
if the Tesseract is kept from us,
无论你躲到什么地方
there will be no realm, no barren moon,
我们也会把你找出来
no crevice where he cannot find you.
你自以为了解痛苦的滋味吗
You think you know pain?
他能让你
He will make you long
渴求痛苦的甜蜜
for something sweet as pain.
-去拿队长的装备  -是  长官
- Stow the captain's gear. - Yes, sir.
罗曼诺夫特工  这位是罗杰斯队长
Agent Romanoff, Captain Rogers.
女士
Ma'am.
舰桥那边找你
They need you on the bridge.
他们开始面部识别追踪了
They're starting the face-trace.
待会儿见
See you there.
在冰层中找到你的事引起了不小的轰动
It was quite the buzz around here, finding you in the ice.
我还以为科尔森会开心得晕过去
I thought Coulson was gonna swoon.
他求你给他的美国队长收藏卡签名了吗
Did he ask you to sign his Captain America trading cards yet?
收藏卡
Trading cards?
绝版珍藏  他很引以为傲
They're vintage. He's very proud.
班纳博士
Dr Banner.
你好
Yeah, hi.
我听说你要来
They told me you would be coming.
我听说你能找到魔方
Word is, you can find the Cube.
你没听说别的事吗
Is that the only word on me?
我只在意这个
Only word I care about.
你一定觉得这一切很奇怪吧
It must be strange for you, all of this.
老实说  我还觉得挺熟悉的
Well, this is actually kind of familiar.
先生们  你们还是快进去吧
Gentlemen, you might want to step inside in a minute.
这里过会儿就难以呼吸了
It's going to get a little hard to breathe.
空勤人员  清空甲板
Flight crew, secure the deck.
这是潜艇吗
Is this a submarine?
是吗
Really?
他们要我待在水下密闭加压的金属罐里吗
They want me in a submerged, pressurised, metal container?
不  这个更糟
No, no, this is much worse.
盘旋动力检查完毕  位置稳定
Hover power check complete. Position cyclic.
动力增大至8%
Increase collective to 8.0%.
准备全速起航
Preparing for maximum performance takeoff.
将输出升到最高
Increase output to capacity.
全速模式
Power plant performing at capacity.
准备就绪
We are clear.
引擎全部开启
All engines operating.
执行神盾局193.6号紧急协议
S.H.I.E.L.D. Emergency Protocol 193.6 in effect.
-已达预定高度  长官  -很好
- We are at level, sir. - Good.
我们消失吧
Let's vanish.
开启反光板
Engage retro-reflection panels.
反光板已开启
Reflection panels engaged.
先生们
Gentlemen.
博士  谢谢你能来
Doctor, thank you for coming.
谢谢你们礼貌地邀请我
Thanks for asking nicely.
我要在这里待上多久
So, how long am I staying?
我们一拿到宇宙魔方
Once we get our hands on the Tesseract,
就会让你走
you're in the wind.
你们进展如何
Where are you with that?
我们扫描了全球所有
We're sweeping every wirelessly accessible
可无线读取的摄像头
camera on the planet.
手机  笔记本
Cell phones, laptops...
只要连接了卫星  就是我们的眼线
If it's connected to a satellite, it's eyes and ears for us.
就这么找还是来不及
That's still not gonna find them in time.
你们得缩小范围
You have to narrow your field.
你能调用多少台光谱仪
How many spectrometers do you have access to?
要多少有多少
How many are there?
联系所有你能找到的实验室
Call every lab you know.
让他们把光谱仪放在房顶
Tell them to put the spectrometers on the roof
校准搜索伽马射线
and calibrate them for gamma rays.
我会根据聚类识别草拟出追踪算法
I'll rough out a tracking algorithm, basic cluster recognition.
至少能排除几个区域
At least we could rule out a few places.
能给我找个工作的地方吗
Do you have somewhere for me to work?
罗曼诺夫特工
Agent Romanoff,
你能带班纳博士去他的实验室吗
could you show Dr. Banner to his laboratory, please?
你准满意  博士  那里一应俱全
You're gonna love it, Doc. We got all the toys.
放去那边
Put it over there.
你从哪里找来的这些人
Where did you find all these people?
神盾局的敌人到处都是  博士
S.H.I.E.L.D. has no shortage of enemies, Doctor.
你要的是这个吗
Is this the stuff you need?
铱  海因里希·赛弗博士
对  铱
Yeah, iridium.
陨石里的物质  能形成反质子
It's found in meteorites. It forms anti-protons.
这东西很难找
It's very hard to get hold of.
要是神盾局知道你需要它就更难找了
Especially if S.H.I.E.L.D. knows you need it.
我可不知道
Well, I didn't know.
宇宙魔方让我看到了太多
The Tesseract has shown me so much.
这些超越了知识  而是真理
It's more than knowledge. It's truth.
我知道
I know.
它让你看到了什么  巴顿特工
What did it show you, Agent Barton?
我的下个目标
My next target.
告诉我你需要什么
Tell me what you need.
一场声东击西
I need a distraction.
和一个眼球
And an eyeball.
那个...太麻烦就算了
I mean, if it's not too much trouble.
哪里  不麻烦
No, no. It's fine.
那是绝版套装
It's a vintage set.
我花了几年才集齐
It took me a couple of years to collect them all.
还很新呢
Near mint.
边角有点泛黄  但...
Slight foxing around the edges, but...
有发现  面部特征67%匹配
We got a hit. A 67% match.
等等  交叉比对显示79%匹配
Wait. Cross match, 79%.
在哪
Location?
德国斯图加特  库宁大街28号
Stuttgart, Germany. 28, Canning Strasse.
他没有躲起来的意思
He's not exactly hiding.
队长
Captain,
该你上场了
you're up.
视网膜扫描-身份识别
认证
海因里希·赛弗博士
开锁
给我跪下
Kneel before me.
我说了
I said
跪下
kneel!
这样不是更简单吗
Is not this simpler?
这难道不是你们的本性吗
Is this not your natural state?
这是人类心照不宣的本性
It's the unspoken truth of humanity,
你们渴望被征服
that you crave subjugation.
自由的光鲜诱惑
The bright lure of freedom
削减了你们人生的乐趣  让你们发狂地追逐权力
diminishes your life's joy in a mad scramble for power,
追逐个性
for identity.
你们天生就该被统治
You were made to be ruled.
到头来
In the end,
你们总会俯首称臣
you will always kneel.
不会向你这样的人
Not to men like you.
从没有像我这样的人
There are no men like me.
总是有像你这样的人
There are always men like you.
瞧瞧这个老头  各位
Look to your elder, people.
我就用他  杀一儆百
Let him be an example.
我上次来德国的时候
You know, the last time I was in Germany,
也遇到一个自以为高高在上的人
and saw a man standing above everybody else,
我们也有点意见不合
we ended up disagreeing.
美国大兵
The soldier.
过时的人
The man out of time.
快要玩完的人可不是我
I'm not the one who's out of time.
洛基  放下武器  马上投降
Loki, drop the weapon and stand down.
跪下
Kneel.
休想
Not today!
到处都是他的分身
The guy's all over the place.
罗曼诺夫特工  想我了吗
Agent Romanoff. You miss me?
广播系统被改写
出招啊  小鹿斑比
Make your move, Reindeer Games.
这才乖
Good move.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark.
队长
Captain.
他开口了吗
Is he saying anything?
什么都没说
Not a word.
带回来再说  我们没时间了
Just get him here. We're low on time.
我有不好的预感
I don't like it.
怎么  因为摇滚明星就这么轻易投降了吗
What? Rock of Ages giving up so easily?
我可不觉得有多轻易
I don't remember it being that easy.
这家伙战斗力很强
This guy packs a wallop.
不管怎样  你一把年纪  身手还算敏捷
Still, you are pretty spry for an older fellow.
你做什么锻炼  普拉提吗
What's your thing, Pilates?
什么
What?
就跟健美操差不多
It's like calisthenics.
你或许是错过了不少事
You might have missed a couple of things
毕竟做了那么久的美队冰棒
doing time as a Capsicle.
弗瑞没告诉我他也找你了
Fury didn't tell me he was calling you in.
是啊  弗瑞还有很多事没告诉你
Yeah, there's a lot of things Fury doesn't tell you.
哪来的闪电
Where's this coming from?
怎么了  你连闪电都怕吗
What's the matter? Are you scared of a little lightning?
我是不喜欢跟随闪电而来的家伙
I'm not overly fond of what follows.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
又来个添乱的
And now there's that guy.
他也是阿斯加德人吗
Another Asgardian?
-你觉得他是友军吗  -无所谓
- That guy's a friendly? - Doesn't matter.
不管他要放了洛基还是杀了他
If he frees Loki or kills him,
宇宙魔方都找不回来了
the Tesseract's lost.
斯塔克  我们需要出击计划
Stark, we need a plan of attack!
我有个计划  出击
I have a plan. Attack.
我劝你别搅这浑水  队长
I'd sit this one out, Cap.
这我做不到
I don't see how I can.
他们是传说人物  基本上就是神
These guys come from legend. They're basically gods.
神只有上帝一个  女士
There's only one God, ma'am.
而且他肯定不会穿成那样
And I'm pretty sure he doesn't dress like that.
宇宙魔方在哪
Where is the Tesseract?
我也想你  哥哥
I missed you, too.
我像是有心情陪你胡闹吗
Do I look to be in a gaming mood?
你应该谢谢我
You should thank me.
没有了彩虹桥
With the Bifrost gone,
奥丁是聚集了多少黑暗能量
how much dark energy did the Allfather have to muster
才把你传送过来
to conjure you here
到你心爱的地球
to your precious Earth?
我以为你死了
I thought you dead.
你为我哀悼了吗
Did you mourn?
我们都哀悼了  我们的父王
We all did. Our father...
是你的父王
Your father.
他把我的身世告诉你了吧
He did tell you my true parentage, did he not?
我们从小一起长大
We were raised together.
一起玩耍  一起战斗
We played together, we fought together.
你都不记得了吗
Do you remember none of that?
我只记得阴影
I remember a shadow.
我一直笼罩在你伟大的阴影之下
Living in the shade of your greatness.
我只记得你将我推下深渊
I remember you tossing me into an abyss.
我本来是王  也本该是王
I, who was, and should be, king!
所以你自认为受了轻视  为了报复我
So you take the world I love as a recompense
就破坏我所爱的世界吗
for your imagined slights?
休想  我会保护地球  洛基
No. The Earth is under my protection, Loki.
那你可保护得真好
And you're doing a marvellous job with that.
人类彼此之间互相残杀
The humans slaughter each other in droves
你却袖手旁观
while you idly fret.
我想要统治他们  这有什么不对
I mean to rule them, as why should I not?
你自以为高他们一等吗
You think yourself above them?
当然
Well, yes.
那你就误解了统治的真谛  弟弟
Then you miss the truth of ruling, brother.
你不适合做王
A throne would suit you ill.
我见识到了你根本不知道的世界
I've seen worlds you've never known about!
在流放期间  奥丁森  我开了眼界
I have grown, Odinson, in my exile.
我见识到了宇宙魔方的真正力量
I have seen the true power of the Tesseract,
等我用它...
and when I wield it...
是谁向你展示了它的力量
Who showed you this power?
你这自封之王听命于谁
Who controls the would-be king?
-我就是王  -在这里不是
- I am a king! - Not here!
你交出宇宙魔方
You give up the Tesseract!
放弃这恶毒的野心
You give up this poisonous dream!
你跟我回家
You come home.
魔方不在我手上
I don't have it.
没有魔方你就不能带我回家
You need the Cube to bring me home.
但我把它转移了  我也不知道它在哪里
But I've sent it off, I know not where.
你给我听好  弟弟
You listen well, brother.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
再动我就要你好看
Do not touch me again.
那你也别动我的东西
Then don't take my stuff.
你根本不知道自己面对的是什么
You have no idea what you're dealing with.
莎翁戏剧的公园公演吗
Shakespeare in the Park?
尔取帘为披风  汝母可知
Doth Mother know you wear-eth her drapes?
这超出了你的能力范围  铁皮人
This is beyond you, metal man.
洛基会受到阿斯加德的制裁
Loki will face Asgardian justice.
只要他交出魔方  他就随你处置  否则
He gives up the Cube, he's all yours. Until then,
你少碍事
stay out of the way.
外地人
Tourist.
好吧
Okay.
能量达到400%
Power at 400% capacity.
这倒是不赖
How about that?
够了
That's enough.
我不知道你想做什么
Now, I don't know what you plan on doing here.
我是来终结洛基的阴谋
I've come here to put an end to Loki's schemes.
那就拿出行动来  把锤子放下
Then prove it. Put that hammer down.
哦不
Yeah... No.
坏主意  他爱死那锤子了
Bad call. He loves his hammer.
你要我放下锤子吗
You want me to put the hammer down?
闹够了吗
Are we done, here?
我先把话说清楚
In case it's unclear,
你要是试图逃跑
if you try to escape,
你就算是刮了一下玻璃
if you so much as scratch that glass,
这个牢笼就会从三万英尺的高空坠落
it's 30,000 feet straight down in a steel trap.
你明白了吗
You get how that works?
现在谁是蚂蚁  谁是靴子
Ant, boot.
这个笼子真不赖
It's an impressive cage.
我猜不是为我造的吧
Not built, I think, for me.
是为比你厉害得多的东西建的
Built for something a lot stronger than you.
我听说了
Oh, I've heard.
一头毫无心智的野兽
A mindless beast.
却装作自己仍是常人
Makes play he's still a man.
你是有多绝望
How desperate are you,
找来这种无法控制的怪物保护你们
that you call on such lost creatures to defend you?
我有多绝望
How desperate am I?
你威胁要向我的世界开战
You threaten my world with war.
你偷走了自己无法掌控的力量
You steal a force you can't hope to control.
你说着和平  却以杀戮为乐
You talk about peace, and you kill because it's fun.
你确实逼得我很绝望
You have made me very desperate.
你或许会因此而后悔
You might not be glad that you did.
失去快到手的东西让你很生气吧
It burns you to have come so close.
得到宇宙魔方  掌握它的力量
To have the Tesseract, to have power,
无限的能量
unlimited power.
用来做什么
And for what?
为全人类点亮一盏明灯
A warm light for all mankind to share.
之后却又见识到了真正的力量
And then to be reminded what real power is.
"真正力量"要是想看杂志了就吱一声
Well, let me know if "real power" wants a magazine or something.
他还真是惹人喜欢
He really grows on you, doesn't he?
洛基是在拖延时间
Loki's gonna drag this out.
托尔  他到底有什么打算
So, Thor, what's his play?
他有一支齐塔瑞大军
He has an army called the Chitauri.
他们不是阿斯加德人  而是来自未知世界
They're not of Asgard, nor any world known.
他打算率领这支大军攻打你们
He means to lead them against your people.
他们会帮助他夺取地球
They will win him the Earth,
我猜他会用宇宙魔方作为交换
in return, I suspect, for the Tesseract.
大军
An army
还是来自外太空
from outer space.
那他还要建个传送门
So, he's building another portal.
这就是他带走艾瑞克·塞尔维格的目的
That's what he needs Erik Selvig for.
塞尔维格
Selvig?
-他是个天体物理学家  -他是我朋友
- He's an astrophysicist. - He's a friend.
洛基对他施了法术  控制了他
Loki has him under some kind of spell,
还有我们的一个特工
along with one of ours.
洛基为什么会这么轻易投降
I want to know why Loki let us take him.
他在这里可没法指挥大军
He's not leading an army from here.
我觉得我们不该一直关注洛基
I don't think we should be focusing on Loki.
那家伙的脑回路不正常
That guy's brain is a bag full of cats.
一看就是个疯子
You could smell crazy on him.
注意你的言辞
Have care how you speak.
即使洛基失去了理智  他还是阿斯加德人
Loki is beyond reason, but he is of Asgard.
还是我弟弟
And he is my brother.
他两天内杀了80个人
He killed 80 people in two days.
他是领养的
He's adopted.
我觉得我们该着重技术问题
I think it's about the mechanics.
铱  他们为什么需要铱
Iridium... What do they need the iridium for?
铱可用作稳定剂
It's a stabilising agent.
我就说  挑个周末
I'm just saying, pick a weekend.
我飞你去波特兰
I'll fly you to Portland.
爱情要维护的啊
Keep love alive.
它能防止传送门自我塌陷
It means the portal won't collapse on itself
像之前在神盾局基地那样
like it did at S.H.I.E.L.D.
别记仇  惊爆点  你真挺有劲
No hard feelings, Point Break. You've got a mean swing.
还能让传送门按洛基的心意
Also, it means the portal can open as wide
想开多大  多久都没问题
and stay open as long, as Loki wants.
升起后桅  调转顶帆
Raise the mizzenmast. Jib the topsails.
那个人在玩小蜜蜂
That man is playing Galaga.
自以为别人看不到  但我看到了
He thought we wouldn't notice, but we did.
弗瑞怎么能看到两边的屏幕
How does Fury even see these?
转身看
He turns.
很累人的样子
Sounds exhausting.
其他原材料
The rest of the raw materials,
巴顿特工都能轻易弄到手
Agent Barton can get his hands on pretty easily.
他只缺少一个要素  能源
The only major component he still needs is a power source
一种高密度能量
of high-energy density.
来激活魔方
Something to kick-start the Cube.
你什么时候对热核天体物理学这么精通了
When did you become an expert in thermonuclear astrophysics?
就昨晚
Last night.
任务资料  塞尔维格的笔记
The packet, Selvig's notes,
萃取论论文
the extraction theory papers.
你们都没做功课吗
Am I the only one who did the reading?
洛基需要什么特定能源吗
Does Loki need any particular kind of power source?
他得把魔方加热到1.2亿开
He would have to heat the Cube to 120-million Kelvin
才能突破库仑势垒
just to break through the Coulomb barrier.
除非  塞尔维格已经想出
Unless Selvig has figured out
稳定量子隧穿效应的方法
how to stabilise the quantum tunnelling effect.
如果他想出来了
Well, if he could do that,
就能用任何一个反应堆实现重离子束聚变
he could achieve heavy ion fusion at any reactor on the planet.
终于有个说人话的了
Finally, someone who speaks English.
是这样吗
Is that what just happened?
幸会  班纳博士
It's good to meet you, Dr Banner.
你对反电子碰撞的研究真是无与伦比
Your work on antielectron collisions is unparalleled.
而且我觉得你失去控制
And I'm a huge fan of the way you lose control
变身狂暴巨怪的样子更是赞
and turn into an enormous green rage-monster.
-谢谢  -班纳博士来这里只是为了追踪魔方
- Thanks. - Dr Banner is only here to track the Cube.
我希望你能和他一起合作
I was hoping you might join him.
从他的权杖入手吧
I would start with that stick of his.
不管有没有魔力
It may be magical,
它的运作方式很像九头蛇的武器
but it works an awful lot like a Hydra weapon.
这我不了解  但权杖的力量来自魔方
I don't know about that, but it is powered by the Cube.
我还想知道
And I would like to know
洛基是怎么用它  把我认识的最机敏的两个人
how Loki used it to turn two of the sharpest men I know
出自《绿野仙踪》
变成了他自己的飞猴
into his personal flying monkeys.
-什么飞猴  我没懂  -我懂
- Monkeys? I do not understand. - I do.
我知道这个梗
I understood that reference.
我们开工吧  博士
Shall we play, Doctor?
这边走  先生
This way, sir.
伽马读数与塞尔维格对宇宙魔方的报告
The gamma readings are definitely consistent with
完全相符
Selvig's reports of the Tesseract.
但处理数据要几周时间
But it's going to take weeks to process.
如果我们绕过他们的主机
If we bypass their mainframe
直接连接主模块
and direct route to the Homer cluster,
速度就能达到每秒六百万亿次浮点运算
we can clock this at around 600 teraflops.
我只带了个牙刷
All I packed was a toothbrush.
你该抽空到斯塔克大厦来
You know, you should come by Stark Tower sometime.
最高10层都是研究开发部
Top ten floors, all R&D.
你肯定喜欢  简直就是糖果乐园
You'd love it. It's Candy Land.
谢了  不过我上次去纽约时
Thanks, but the last time I was in New York,
把哈莱姆区给砸烂了
I kind of broke Harlem.《无敌浩克》
我保证不给你压力
Well, I promise a stress-free environment.
不紧张  也不吓唬你
No tension, no surprises.
这么淡定
Nothing?
你疯了吗
Are you nuts?
谁知道呢
Jury's out.
你还真能压得住火气  你有什么诀窍
You really have got a lid on it, haven't you? What's your secret?
舒缓爵士乐  邦哥鼓  还是抽一大袋大麻
Mellow jazz, bongo drums, huge bag of weed?
你把所有的事都当成笑话吗
Is everything a joke to you?
只有好笑的事
Funny things are.
危及航母上所有人的生命安全并不好笑
Threatening the safety of everyone on this ship isn't funny.
-无意冒犯  博士  -没关系
- No offence, Doc. - It's all right,
我要是连这都受不住  也不会来了
I wouldn't have come aboard if I couldn't handle pointy things.
你太小心了  大块头
You're tip-toeing, big man.
你该放开点
You need to strut.
而你该专心解决问题  斯塔克先生
And you need to focus on the problem, Mr Stark.
你觉得我没有吗
Do you think I'm not?
弗瑞为什么现在才找我们  而不是之前
Why did Fury call us in? Why now? Why not before?
他对我们隐瞒了什么
What isn't he telling us?
信息不全  我就无法解答
I can't do the equation unless I have all the variables.
你是说弗瑞有什么没告诉我们吗
You think Fury's hiding something?
他是间谍  队长  他是间谍之王
He's a spy. Captain, he's "The" Spy.
他的秘密会下崽
His secrets have secrets.
你也在琢磨这事  对吧
It's bugging him, too. Isn't it?
我只想完成手头的工作...
I just want to finish my work here, and...
博士
Doctor?
为全人类点亮一盏明灯
"A warm light for all mankind."
关于魔方  洛基挖苦弗瑞的那句话
Loki's jab at Fury about the Cube.
我也听到了
I heard it.
我认为他是在指你
I think that was meant for you.
即使巴顿没告诉洛基斯塔克大厦的事
Even if Barton didn't tell Loki about the tower,
新闻上也到处都是了
it was still all over the news.
斯塔克大厦
The Stark Tower?
就是纽约那幢又大又丑...的大楼吗
That big, ugly building in New York?
为大楼供能的方舟反应堆是自给能源
It's powered by an arc reactor, a self-sustaining energy source.
那栋大楼一年内都不需要外部能源吧
That building will run itself for, what, a year?
那还只是个原型
It's just the prototype.
我算是当今清洁能源界的唯一人
I'm kind of the only name in clean energy right now.
他就是这个意思
That's what he's getting at.
所以  神盾局为什么
So, why didn't S.H.I.E.L.D.
不把他招进宇宙魔方计划
bring him in on the Tesseract project?
更何况  他们为什么要染指能源业
What are they doing in the energy business in the first place?
我应该调查一下
I should probably look into that
等我的解密程序破解了
once my decryption programme finishes
所有的神盾局加密文件
breaking into all of S.H.I.E.L.D.'s secure files.
不好意思  你说什么
I'm sorry. Did you say...
我一到舰桥  贾维斯就开始运行破解程序了
Jarvis has been running it since I hit the bridge.
只要几个小时  我就能知道
In a few hours, I'll know
神盾局内部所有不可告人的秘密
every dirty secret S.H.I.E.L.D. has ever tried to hide.
吃蓝莓吗
Blueberry?
你还想不通为什么神盾局不让你加入吗
Yet you're confused about why they didn't want you around.
intelligence有智力和情报两种意思
情报部门的人还惧怕天才吗
An intelligence organisation that fears intelligence?
可真是说不过去啊
Historically, not awesome.
我认为洛基是想让我们神经紧张
I think Loki's trying to wind us up.
他可是要发动战争的人
This is a man who means to start a war
如果我们不能保持专注  他就得逞了
and if we don't stay focused, he'll succeed.
我们接到命令  就要服从
We have orders. We should follow them.
服从命令不是我的风格
Following's not really my style.
你只在乎你的风格  是吧
And you're all about style, aren't you?
这个房间里的人
Of the people in this room,
是谁  首先穿得花里胡哨
which one is, A, wearing a spangly outfit,
其次  根本毫无用处
and, B, not of use?
史蒂夫  你真的不觉得这有点奇怪吗
Steve, tell me none of this smells a little funky to you.
找到魔方就是了
Just find the Cube.
他就是我爸一直念念不忘的家伙吗
That's the guy my dad never shut up about?
他们是不是继续把他冻着比较好
I'm wondering if they shouldn't have kept him on ice.
关于洛基他说得对
The guy's not wrong about Loki.
他确实胜我们一筹
He does have the jump on us.
他不过是有个看着挺唬人的炸弹
What he's got is an Acme dynamite kit.
早晚会把他自己炸飞
It's going to blow up in his face.
到时候我就等着看好戏
And I'm going to be there when it does.
那我还是等着看报纸好了
Yeah. I'll read all about it.
或者你会和我们一起披挂上阵
Or you'll be suiting up with the rest of us.
要知道  我可不穿盔甲
You see, I don't get a suit of armour.
我就像神经一样暴露在外
I'm exposed. Like a nerve.
简直是一场噩梦
It's a nightmare.
我身体里有一堆弹片
You know, I've got a cluster of shrapnel
时刻都在往我心脏里爬
trying every second to crawl its way into my heart.
被这个挡住了
This stops it.
这个小小的光环  它已经是我的一部分了
This little circle of light, it's part of me now,
而不仅仅是盔甲
not just armour.
这是种可怕的特权
It's a terrible privilege.
-可你能控制它  -因为我找到了方法
- But you can control it. - Because I learned how.
我们不一样
It's different.
你的"意外事故"我都听说了
I read all about your accident.
你受了那么强的伽玛辐射  本该是死定了
That much gamma exposure should have killed you.
所以你是说绿巨人...
So you're saying that the Hulk...
那个家伙救了我吗
The other guy saved my life?
不错
That's nice.
这么想挺好  可他为什么要救我
It's a nice sentiment. Saved it for what?
也许以后就知道了
I guess we'll find out.
那个答案你未必喜欢
You may not enjoy that.
但你也许会喜欢
And you just might.
安全仓库
洛基带走了博士之后
As soon as Loki took the doctor,
我们转移了简·福斯特
we moved Jane Foster.
特罗瑟姆[挪威城市]有座很好的天文台
They've got an excellent observatory in Troms?
昨天突然有人请她去做顾问
She was asked to consult there very suddenly yesterday.
酬金不菲  搭乘私人飞机  地处偏远
Handsome fee, private plane, very remote.
她不会有事
She'll be safe.
谢谢
Thank you.
洛基带走艾瑞克·塞尔维格绝非偶然
It's no accident, Loki taking Erik Selvig.
等洛基达成目的  还不知会如何对他
I dread what he plans for him once he's done.
艾瑞克是个好人
Erik is a good man.
他经常说起你
He talks about you a lot.
你改变了他的生活
You changed his life.
你还改变了这里的一切
You changed everything around here.
还是保持原样的好
They were better as they were.
在阿斯加德  我们自视高人一等
We pretend on Asgard that we're more advanced
却像俾施泰姆一样来这胡作非为
but we come here, battling like bilge snipe.
-像什么  -俾施泰姆
- Like what? - Bilge snipe.
就是那种有鳞甲和大角的巨兽
You know, huge, scaly, big antlers.
-地球上没有吗  -应该没有
- You don't have those? - I don't think so.
那东西很可恶
Well, they are repulsive.
途经之地万物尽毁
And they trample everything in their path.
我第一次来地球时  引来了洛基的愤怒
When I first came to Earth, Loki's rage followed me here,
人类为此遭受劫难
and your people paid the price.
现在历史又重演
And now, again.
年少无知的我渴望战争
In my youth, I courted war.
战争还没开始呢
War hasn't started yet.
你能从洛基口中问出宇宙魔方的下落吗
You think you could make Loki tell us where the Tesseract is?
不知道  洛基的心思深不可测
I do not know. Loki's mind is far afield.
他不仅渴望权力  还想要报复我
It's not just power he craves, it's vengeance, upon me.
任何痛苦都不能让他放弃自己的野心
There's no pain would prise his need from him.
很多人都曾这么认为
A lot of guys think that
直到他们尝到真正的痛苦
until the pain starts.
你要我做什么
What are you asking me to do?
我要问你  你愿意做什么
I'm asking, what are you prepared to do?
洛基现在是犯人
Loki is a prisoner.
但我为什么觉得
Then why do I feel like
他是唯一想待在这艘航母上的人
he's the only person on this boat that wants to be here?
能偷偷接近我的人可不多
There's not many people who can sneak up on me.
可你猜到我会来
But you figured I'd come.
没这么早
After.
我以为弗瑞在用尽所有折磨后
After whatever tortures Fury can concoct,
才会派你来  假意友好  来安抚我
you would appear as a friend, as a balm.
我就会合作了
And I would cooperate.
我想知道你对巴顿特工做了什么
I want to know what you've done to Agent Barton.
我开拓了他的心智
I would say I've expanded his mind.
等你赢了
And once you've won,
等你成了王
once you're king of the mountain,
他的心智会怎么样
what happens to his mind?
你爱他吗  罗曼诺夫特工
Is this love, Agent Romanoff?
小孩子才说爱  我是欠他人情
Love is for children. I owe him a debt.
说来听听
Tell me.
我进神盾局之前  我...
Before I worked for S.H.I.E.L. D... I...
我早已声名远扬
Well, I made a name for myself.
我有着独特的技能
I have a very specific skill set.
我不在乎为谁工作  或是对付谁
I didn't care who I used it for, or on.
我上了神盾局的黑名单
I got on S.H.I.E.L.D.'s radar in a bad way.
他们派巴顿特工来杀我
Agent Barton was sent to kill me.
但他改了主意
He made a different call.
要是我保证放他一条生路  你要怎么回报我
And what will you do if I vow to spare him?
我不会放了你
Not let you out.
我知道  可这多有趣
No, but I like this.
整个世界都危在旦夕  你却为一个人讨价还价
Your world in the balance, and you bargain for one man.
政权的颠覆司空见惯
Regimes fall every day.
我不会纠结这个  我可是俄罗斯人
I tend not to weep over that. I'm Russian.
以前是
Or I was.
那你现在又算什么
And what are you now?
其实这事没这么复杂
It's really not that complicated.
我欠了债  我想要偿还
I got red in my ledger, I'd like to wipe it out.
你能吗
Can you?
那么多的债  你真的还得清吗
Can you wipe out that much red?
德雷科夫的女儿
Dreykov's daughter,
圣保罗
St Paulo,
医院的火灾
the hospital fire?
巴顿把一切都告诉我了
Barton told me everything.
你血债累累  沾满双手
Your ledger is dripping. It's gushing red
你以为救一个比你强不到哪去的人
and you think saving a man no more virtuous than yourself
能改变什么吗
will change anything?
多廉价的多愁善感
This is the basest sentimentality.
就像在祈祷的孩子
This is a child at prayer.
可悲至极
Pathetic!
你欺骗  杀戮
You lie and kill
为骗子和杀手服务
in the service of liars and killers.
发现病毒  非法入侵
你自以为清高  遵循自己的准则
You pretend to be separate, to have your own code,
粉饰你所犯下的罪行
something that makes up for the horrors.
但那是你的一部分
But they are part of you.
永远无法抹去
And they will never go away.
我会留着巴顿  我会让他杀了你
I won't touch Barton, not until I make him kill you.
他深知你的恐惧
Slowly, intimately,
他会一点一点亲手杀了你
in every way he knows you fear.
之后我再唤醒他  给他时间欣赏自己的杰作
And then he'll wake just long enough to see his good work
等他痛苦哀嚎的时候  我再要了他的命
and when he screams, I'll split his skull.
这就是我还的价  你这没用的婊子
This is my bargain, you mewling quim.
你是个怪物
You're a monster.
不
Oh, no.
怪物是你带来的
You brought the monster.
所以是班纳
So, Banner.
那就是你的计划
That's your play.
什么
What?
洛基想要让绿巨人变身
Loki means to unleash the Hulk.
别让班纳出实验室  我马上就到
Keep Banner in the lab. I'm on my way.
让托尔也过去
Send Thor as well.
谢谢你的合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
你在干什么  斯塔克先生
What are you doing, Mr Stark?
我也想问你同样的问题
Kind of been wondering the same thing about you.
你该去搜寻宇宙魔方的下落
You're supposed to be locating the Tesseract.
没错  搜索模型已经锁定
We are. The model's locked
正在扫描搜索信号
and we're sweeping for the signature now.
一有结果
When we get a hit,
就能把范围缩小到半英里内
we'll have the location within half a mile.
嗯  然后你就能拿回魔方  稍安毋躁
Yeah, then you get your Cube back. No muss, no fuss.
二阶是什么
What is "Phase 2"?
二阶是神盾局利用魔方制造武器
Phase 2 is S.H.I.E.L.D. uses the Cube to make weapons.
抱歉  电脑对我来说太慢了
Sorry, computer was moving a little slow for me.
罗杰斯  我们搜集所有与宇宙魔方有关的东西
Rogers, we gathered everything related to the Tesseract.
这不代表我们...
This does not mean that we're making...
不好意思  尼克
I'm sorry, Nick.
你还有什么好说的吗
What were you lying?
我错了  局长
I was wrong, Director.
这个世界还是一点没变
The world hasn't changed a bit.
这事你知道吗
Did you know about this?
你要不要
You want to think about
离开这里  博士
removing yourself from this environment, Doctor?
我本在加尔各答[印]  离这远着呢
I was in Calcutta. I was pretty well removed.
洛基在操控你
Loki is manipulating you.
那你一直以来做的又是什么
And you've been doing what, exactly?
你肯来不是被我的魅力折服才来的
You didn't come here because I bat my eyelashes at you.
对  我也不会因为你突然神经质了就走
Yes, and I'm not leaving because suddenly you get a little twitchy.
我要知道神盾局为什么
I'd like to know why S.H.I.E.L.D.
利用宇宙魔方开发大规模杀伤性武器
is using the Tesseract to build weapons of mass destruction.
因为他
Because of him.
我
Me?
去年   一个外星人来到地球
Last year, Earth had a visitor from another planet
引发了一场恶战  结果移平了一座小镇
who had a grudge match that levelled a small town.
我们不仅知道了宇宙中有其他生命存在
We learned that not only are we not alone
还发现我们的战斗力远远不及他们
but we are hopelessly, hilariously, outgunned.
我的人民只想与地球和平相处
My people want nothing but peace with your planet.
可你们不是唯一的外星生命吧
But you're not the only people out there, are you?
你们也不是唯一的威胁
And you're not the only threat.
宇宙中充满了比我们强大的生物
The world's filling up with people who can't be matched,
没有人能控制他们
that can't be controlled.
就像你们控制不了魔方吗
Like you controlled the Cube?
你们利用宇宙魔方制造武器
Your work with the Tesseract
才会招来洛基和他的同伙
is what drew Loki to it, and his allies.
这是给其他种族发出的信号
It is a signal to all the realms
宣告地球准备好展开高级战争
that the Earth is ready for a higher form of war.
高级
A higher form?
这是无奈之举
You forced our hand.
我们必须有所准备
We had to come up with something.
"核威慑"
A nuclear deterrent.
因为那样总能平息所有事态
Because that always calms everything right down.
别忘了你们家族的发家史  斯塔克
Remind me again how you made your fortune, Stark.
如果斯塔克还在造军火  他肯定也脱不了...
I'm sure if he still made weapons, Stark would be neck-deep...
等等  矛头怎么指向我了
Hold on. How is this now about me?
怎么  你不总是焦点吗
I'm sorry, isn't everything?
我以为人类要比这文明
I thought humans were more evolved than this.
不好意思  人类跑去你的星球捣乱了吗
Excuse me, did we come to your planet and blow stuff up?
你居然这么不信任你们的守护者
You treat your champions with such mistrust.
你们怎么这么幼稚
Are you boys really that naive?
神盾局会监视所有潜在威胁
S.H.I.E.L.D. monitors potential threats.
美国队长也是威胁吗
Captain America's on threat watch?
我们都是
We all are.
等等  你也上黑名单了吗
Wait, you're on that list?
你和愤怒的蜜蜂[游戏]谁更靠前
Are you above or below angry bees?
斯塔克  我发誓  你要是再说一句俏皮话...
Stark, so help me God, if you make one more wisecrack...
你这是口头恐吓  我感到威胁了
Threat! Verbal threat. I feel threatened.
-放尊重点  -尊重什么
- Show some respect. - Respect what?
66B号运输机  请说确认口令
Transport Six-Six-Bravo, please relay confirm codes.
系统里有你的资料  但没有航行记录
I've got you on the computer, but not on the day log.
请上报运输货物  完毕
What is your haul? Over.
武器弹药  完毕
Arms and ammunition. Over.
你口口声声说要控制  却崇尚混乱
You speak of control, yet you court chaos.
这就是他的作风  不是吗
That's his M.O., isn't it?
我们算是团队吗
I mean, what are we, a team?
不  我们在一起只会产生混乱
No, we're a chemical mixture that makes chaos.
我们...就是个定时炸弹
We're a time bomb.
你最好别插嘴
You need to step away.
他为什么就不能发泄一下呢
Why shouldn't the guy let off a little steam?
这你清楚得很  少胡闹
You know damn well why. Back off!
我倒想看看你有没有本事让我不闹
I'm starting to want you to make me.
是吗  你只是穿着铁甲威风罢了
Yeah. Big man in a suit of armour.
没有铁甲  你又算什么
Take that off, what are you?
超级天才  亿万富翁  花心萝卜  慈善人士
Genius, billionaire, playboy, philanthropist.
我认识很多人  即使没有这些也比你强上十倍
I know guys with none of that worth ten of you.
我看过关于你的资料
I've seen the footage.
你只在乎你自己
The only thing you really fight for is yourself.
你不会做出牺牲
You're not the guy to make the sacrifice play,
不会匍在铁丝网上让战友爬过去
to lay down on a wire and let the other guy crawl over you.
要是我就剪断铁丝网
I think I would just cut the wire.
总是有歪门邪道
Always a way out.
你也许不是威胁
You may not be a threat
但你最好别再充英雄了
but you better stop pretending to be a hero.
英雄  你那样的英雄吗
A hero? Like you?
你就是个实验品  罗杰斯
You're a laboratory experiment, Rogers.
你的一切超凡也不过是一瓶血清给的
Everything special about you came out of a bottle.
穿上铁甲  我们来战
Put on the suit. Let's go a few rounds.
你们人类真渺小
You people are so petty and tiny.
这也叫团队
Yeah, this is a team.
罗曼诺夫特工  请你护送
Agent Romanoff, would you escort
班纳博士回他的...
Dr Banner back to his...
去哪  你把我的房间给别人了
Where? You rented my room.
那个囚室只是以防...
The cell was just in case...
以防你必须杀我
In case you needed to kill me.
但你杀不了我  我知道  我自己试过
But you can't. I know, I tried.
我很低落  看不到出路
I got low. I didn't see an end.
所以我吞枪自杀  而那家伙把子弹吐了出来
So, I put a bullet in my mouth, and the other guy spit it out.
所以我活了下去
So I moved on.
专注于帮助别人  我本来很好
I focused on helping other people. I was good.
直到你们把我拉来这场闹剧
Until you dragged me back into this freak show
还危及所有人的安全
and put everyone here at risk.
你不是想知道我有什么诀窍吗  罗曼诺夫特工
You want to know my secret, Agent Romanoff?
我怎么保持冷静的诀窍
You want to know how I stay calm?
班纳博士
Dr Banner,
放下权杖
put down the sceptre.
搜索中...
能量信号匹配度  94%
能量信号匹配度  95%
找到了
Got it.
抱歉  伙计们
Sorry, kids,
你们没机会看我亮绝活了
you don't get to see my party trick after all.
找到宇宙魔方了吗
You located the Tesseract?
我能更快赶过去
I could get there fastest.
宇宙魔方是阿斯加德的  人类无法控制
The Tesseract belongs on Asgard. No human is a match for it.
-你不能自己去  -你要阻止我吗
- You're not going alone. - You're gonna stop me?
等你穿上铁甲再说
Put on the suit, let's find out.
打老年人我毫无压力
I'm not afraid to hit an old man.
快穿上铁甲
Put on the suit.
能量信号匹配度  98%
能量信号匹配度  99%
能量信号匹配度  100%
天啊
Oh, my God.
去穿铁甲
Put on the suit.
听你的
Yeah.
全员就位
All hands to stations.
-希尔  -航母外部发生爆炸
- Hill! - External detonation.
-3号引擎停机  -我们遭到了袭击
- Number three engine is down. - We've been hit.
-能修好吗  -3号引擎失火
- Can they get it running? - Fire in engine three!
-什么情况  -涡轮机还算完好
- Talk to me. - Turbine looks mostly intact
但我们在飞行状态下
but it's impossible to get out there to make repairs
无法进入故障区维修
while we're in the air.
再失去一个引擎我们就要坠毁了
If we lose one more engine we won't be.
派人出去修理引擎
Somebody's got to get outside and patch that engine.
-斯塔克  听到了吗  -我这就去
- Stark, you copy that? - I'm on it.
科尔森  启动关押区防御性封锁
Coulson, initiate defensive lockdown in the detention section,
再去军械库
then get to the armoury.
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff?
我们没事
We're okay.
没事的吧
We're okay, right?
-别让引擎启动  -是  长官
- Keep that engine down! - Yes, sir.
去关押区  先关闭摄像头
Detention, wait for cameras to go dark.
-是  -跟我来
- Got it. - Stay close.
到第4层
Let's go, Level 4.
3号引擎  那边见
Engine three. I'll meet you there.
博士
Doctor?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
你得挺住  不能正中洛基下怀
You got to fight it. This is just what Loki wants.
我们不会有事的  听我说
We're going to be okay. Listen to me.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
不会有事  好吗
We're going to be okay. All right?
我用生命发誓  我一定会救你出去
I swear on my life I will get you out of this.
你不会再被牵扯进来  再也不...
You will walk away and never ever...
你的命
Your life?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
调转航母  航向180  向南行进
Bring the carrier about to a 1-8-0, heading south!
-把航母开向海面  -我们在盲目飞行
- Take us to the water! - We're flying blind.
引擎故障后  导航系统重置了
Navigation's recalibrating after the engine failure.
天上有太阳吗
Is the sun coming up?
-有  长官  -那就在太阳右边飞
- Yes, sir. - Then put it on the left.
开往海面
Get us over water.
再有涡轮熄火就要坠毁了
One more turbine goes down, and we drop.
谢谢
Thanks.
斯塔克
Stark!
斯塔克  我来了
Stark, I'm here!
很好
Good.
看看是什么情况
Let's see what we've got.
我得先修复超导冷却系统
I got to get this superconducting coolant system back online
之后才能进入转轮
before I can access the rotors,
清理残骸
work on dislodging the debris.
你去引擎控制面板那里
I need you to get to that engine control panel
告诉我哪些继电器过载了
and tell me which relays are in overload position.
你看到了什么
What does it look like in there?
电力设备
It seems to run on some form of electricity.
嗯  你也没说错
Well, you're not wrong.
我们不是敌人  班纳
We are not your enemies, Banner.
快清醒过来
Try to think!
好  继电器正常了
Okay, the relays are intact.
接下来怎么做
What's our next move?
就算我清理了残骸
Even if I clear the rotors,
没有助力  转轮也无法重新启动
this thing won't re-engage without a jump.
我得进去推着它转
I'm going to have to get in there and push.
转速上升了你就会被切碎
If that thing gets up to speed, you'll get shredded.
定子控制器
That stator control unit
能翻转磁极
can reverse the polarity long enough
直至磁悬浮解除  就能...
to disengage maglev and that could...
说人话
Speak English!
看到红色控制杆了吗
You see that red lever?
它能让转轮减速  给我飞出来的时间
It will slow the rotors down long enough for me to get out.
待在那里  等我指令
Stand by it. Wait for my word.
撤离下层机库甲板上的全部人员
We need full evac on the lower hangar bay.
小心手雷
Grenade!
有人入侵
We've got a perimeter breach!
敌人身着神盾局装备
Hostiles are in S.H.I.E.L.D. gear.
全员注意
Call-outs at every junction.
绿巨人和托尔在4层研发层
We have the Hulk and Thor on Research Level 4.
2层和3层的摄像头被破坏
Levels 2 and 3 are dark.
长官  绿巨人会把这里彻底毁掉
Sir, the Hulk will tear this place apart!
那就吸引他的注意力
Get his attention.
60护航机前往Y型区  火力牵制敌人
Escort 6-0, proceed to Wishbone and engage hostile.
保持距离
Don't get too close.
收到
Copy.
锁定目标
Target acquired.
开火
Target engaged.
目标火了  他发火了
Target angry, target angry!
你们不可能通过这道门  究竟想...
You're not getting through here, so what the hell...
1号引擎出现故障
1号引擎停机了
Engine one is now in shut-down.
我们正在失控下坠
We are in an uncontrolled descent.
长官  1号引擎彻底停转
Sir, we've lost all power in engine one.
是巴顿  他毁了我们的系统
It's Barton. He took out our systems.
他去关押层了
He's headed for the detention level.
有人收到吗
Does anybody copy?
我是罗曼诺夫特工
This is Agent Romanoff.
我收到了
I copy.
斯塔克  航母在下坠
Stark, we're losing altitude.
嗯  发现了
Yeah, I noticed.
不
No!
你还能不能吸取教训了
Are you ever not going to fall for that?
人类认为我们是不死之身
The humans think us immortal.
那就检验一下吧
Should we test that?
请你退到一边去
Move away, please.
你喜欢吗
You like this?
你派来毁灭者后  我们研发了这个原型机
We started working on the prototype after you sent the Destroyer.
我都不清楚它的威力
Even I don't know what it does.
你想试试看吗
Do you want to find out?
不
No!
塔莎
Tasha?
你输定了
You're going to lose.
是吗
Am I?
因为你的本性
It's in your nature.
你们那些英雄已经分崩离析
Your heroes are scattered.
你们的飞行堡垒也将要坠落
Your floating fortress falls from the sky.
我还有什么好担心的
Where is my disadvantage?
你没有信念
You lack conviction.
我觉得我...
I don't think I'm...
威力不小嘛
So, that's what it does.
高度
队长  扳控制杆
Cap, hit the lever.
等我一下
I need a minute here!
扳控制杆
Lever
快点
now!
救命
Help!
对不起  头儿
Sorry, boss.
被那神逃走了
The god rabbited.
保持清醒
Just stay awake.
看着我
Eyes on me.
不行了  我得离岗了
No, I'm clocking out here.
我不批准
Not an option.
没关系  头儿
It's okay, boss.
想要他们成为真正的团队
This was never gonna work
就得给他们点...
if they didn't have something
动...
to...
科尔森特工负伤了
Agent Coulson is down.
医疗队赶过去了
A medical team is on its way to your location.
他们已经到了
They're here.
他们宣布死亡了
They called it.
这是在菲尔·科尔森外套口袋里找到的
These were in Phil Coulson's jacket.
看来他没来得及找你要签名
I guess he never did get you to sign them.
我们现在完全停摆
We're dead in the air up here.
通讯中断  魔方不知所踪
Our communications, the location of the Cube,
班纳和托尔也下落不明
Banner, Thor...
我已经山穷水尽了
I got nothing for you.
还失去了最得力的属下
I lost my one good eye.
也许这是我活该
Maybe I had that coming.
没错
Yes,
我们是想利用宇宙魔方制造武器
we were going to build an arsenal with the Tesseract.
但我并没有将所有希望放在这个上面
I never put all my chips on that number, though,
因为我还有个更大胆的计划
because I was playing something even riskier.
我有个设想  这事斯塔克知道
There was an idea, Stark knows this,
叫做"复仇者计划"
called the Avengers Initiative.
是将一些能力超群的人聚集在一起
The idea was to bring together a group of remarkable people
看他们组成的团队是不是更强大
to see if they could become something more.
看他们是不是能在危急时刻并肩战斗
To see if they could work together when we needed them to,
去打赢那些我们赢不了的战争
to fight the battles that we never could.
菲尔·科尔森到死都相信这个设想
Phil Coulson died still believing in that idea.
他相信英雄
In heroes.
好吧
Well,
这个观念是过时了
it's an old-fashioned notion.
你从天上掉下来
You fell out of the sky.
我伤着谁了吗
Did I hurt anybody?
这附近也没人给你伤
There's nobody around here to get hurt.
不过你倒是把鸽子都吓坏了
You did scare the hell out of some pigeons, though.
那真走运
Lucky.
或许是你瞄得准
Or just good aim.
落下来的时候你还醒着呢
You were awake when you fell.
-你都看见了吗  -都看到了
- You saw? - The whole thing.
你穿透屋顶摔下来
Right through the ceiling.
又大又绿还光着屁股
Big and green and buck-ass nude.
给
Here.
本来没觉得你能穿上这个
Didn't think those would fit you
直到你缩小到普通人的身材
until you shrunk down to a regular-size feller.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是外星人吗
Are you an alien?
什么
What?
你是外太空来的人吗
From outer space, an alien.
不是
No.
这样啊  那你可病得不轻啊  孩子
Well, then, son, you've got a condition.
克林特  你不会有事的
Clint. You're going to be all right.
是吗
You know that?
你确定吗
Is that what you know?
我不能松懈
I've got no window.
我得把他赶出去
I have to flush him out.
你得稳定下来  这需要时间
You got to level out. It's going to take time.
你不明白
You don't understand.
你知道被人夺去意志  肆意摆布的滋味吗
Have you ever had someone take your brain and play?
把你的意识排除在外  塞进另一个自己
Pull you out and stuff something else in?
你知道那种被摧毁的感觉吗
Do you know what it's like to be unmade?
你知道我明白那种感觉
You know that I do.
我怎么恢复的
Why am I back?
你怎么把他弄走的
How did you get him out?
我重校准了你的意识
Cognitive recalibration.
就是狠狠地砸了你的脑袋
I hit you really hard on the head.
谢谢
Thanks.
娜塔莎
Natasha...
我杀了多少特...
How many agents did I...
别
Don't.
别这么折磨自己  克林特
Don't do that to yourself, Clint.
错的是洛基
This is Loki.
是怪物和魔法
This is monsters and magic,
是我们从未对付过的敌人
and nothing we were ever trained for.
洛基  他跑了吗
Loki, did he get away?
是的
Yeah.
你知道他去哪里了吗
I don't suppose you know where.
这我不需要知道
I didn't need to know.
我没问
I didn't ask.
不过他很快就会行动
He's going to make his play soon, though.
就在今天
Today.
我们得阻止他
We got to stop him.
是吗  我们都有谁
Yeah? Who's "We"?
不知道  还剩下的人吧
I don't know. Whoever's left.
嗯
Well,
要是我能一箭射穿洛基的眼窝
if I put an arrow through Loki's eye socket,
应该就能睡个好觉了
I would sleep better, I suppose.
这话才像你
Now you sound like you.
可你不像你
But you don't.
你是间谍  不是战士
You're a spy, not a soldier.
现在你却要去冲锋陷阵  为什么
Now you want to wade into a war. Why?
洛基把你怎么了
What did Loki do to you?
没怎么  我只是...
He didn't. I just...
娜塔莎
Natasha.
我被他动摇了
I've been compromised.
我欠了债
I got red in my ledger.
我想要还债
I would like to wipe it out.
他结婚了吗
Was he married?
没有
No.
有个女友  好像是大提琴手
There was a cellist, I think.
真可惜
I'm sorry.
他看着人不错
He seemed like a good man.
他就是个笨蛋
He was an idiot.
为什么  因为他有信仰吗
Why? For believing?
因为他单独去对付洛基
For taking on Loki alone.
那叫尽职尽责
He was doing his job.
那叫自不量力  他该等待支援
He was out of his league. He should have waited.
他该...
He should have...
有时候没有别的选择  托尼
Sometimes there isn't a way out, Tony.
是啊  这话真耳熟
Right, I've heard that before.
这是你第一次失去战友吗
Is this the first time you lost a soldier?
我们不是战士
We are not soldiers.
我不会听令于弗瑞
I'm not marching to Fury's fife.
我也不会
Neither am I.
他也该为洛基犯下的罪行负责
He's got the same blood on his hands that Loki does.
但现在我们必须既往不咎
But right now, we got to put that behind us
共同对付外敌
and get this done.
洛基需要一个能量源
Loki needs a power source.
要是我们能列出...
If we can put together a list...
他把战争变成了私仇
He made it personal.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
这就是重点  这就是洛基的目的
That is the point. That's Loki's point.
他为什么要直捣我们的老巢
He hit us all right where we live. Why?
为了击溃我们
To tear us apart.
是啊  分散击破的确很聪明
Yeah, divide and conquer is great
但他知道他必须要铲除我们
but he knows he has to take us out to win, right?
这才是他的目的
That's what he wants.
他要打败我们  还要别人看到
He wants to beat us, he wants to be seen doing it.
他想要观众
He wants an audience.
对  我在斯图加特就碰上他的表演
Right. I caught his act in Stuttgart.
没错  那只是试映
Yeah, that was just previews.
这可是首演之夜
This is opening night.
而洛基就是这场华丽闹剧的主角
And Loki, he's a full-tilt diva, right?
他渴望鲜花和掌声
He wants flowers, he wants parades.
他要一座高耸入云的纪念碑  上面刻着他的名字
He wants a monument built to the skies with his name plastered...
我靠
Son of a bitch.
斯塔克
该走了
Time to go.
-去哪里  -路上说
- Go where? - I'll tell you on the way.
你会开飞机吗
Can you fly one of those jets?
我会
I can.
你有战斗服吗
You got a suit?
有
Yeah.
那就换装
Then suit up.
未经允许你们不能登机
Hey, you guys aren't authorised to be in here.
孩子  别说了
Son, just don't.
长官
Sir.
希尔特工
Agent Hill.
那些卡片
Those cards,
是放在科尔森的衣柜里  而不是外套
they were in Coulson's locker, not in his jacket.
他们需要点动力
They needed the push.
6号停机坪有人私自起飞
We have an unauthorised departure from Bay 6.
他们找到洛基了
They found him.
想尽一切办法恢复通讯
Get our communications back up, whatever you have to do.
-我要监控全局  -是  长官
- I want eyes on everything. - Yes, sir.
先生  我关闭了方舟反应堆
Sir, I've turned off the arc reactor
但那个装置已经自续供能了
but the device is already self-sustaining.
关掉它  塞尔维格博士
Shut it down, Dr Selvig.
太迟了
It's too late!
她停不下来了
She can't stop now.
她有东西要给我们看
She wants to show us something!
一个新宇宙
A new universe.
好吧
Okay.
那层屏障是纯能量
The barrier is pure energy.
无法打破
It's unbreachable.
看出来了
Yeah, I got that.
更换计划
Plan B.
先生  马克7型还不能使用
Sir, the Mark 7 is not ready for deployment.
那就不要轮子了  我们没时间了
Then skip the spinning rims. We're on the clock.
你是来求我开恩的吧
Please tell me you're going to appeal to my humanity.
其实我是来威胁你的
Actually, I'm planning to threaten you.
那你可不该把铁甲脱了
You should have left your armour on for that.
是啊
Yeah.
那一身穿得有些旧了
It's seen a bit of mileage,
你还拿着金闪闪的命运之杖呢
and you've got the glow stick of destiny.
来一杯吗
Would you like a drink?
拖时间也没有用
Stalling me won't change anything.
不不不  是威胁
No, no. Threatening.
你真的不喝吗
No drink? Are you sure?
我可要来一杯
I'm having one.
齐塔瑞大军要来了  谁都无法阻止
The Chitauri are coming. Nothing will change that.
我还怕什么
What have I to fear?
复仇者联盟
The Avengers.
是我们自己起的名字  就是一队人
That's what we call ourselves. We're sort of like a team.
地球最强英雄组合什么的
"Earth's mightiest heroes"-type thing.
我见识过了
Yes, I've met them.
好吧
Yeah.
我承认磨合是要花些时间
It takes us a while to get any traction, I'll give you that one.
不过我们还是来列一下吧
But let's do a head count, here.
我们有你的半神哥哥
Your brother, the demigod,
一个超级战士
a super soldier,
不负盛名的不死传奇
a living legend who kind of lives up to the legend.
一个有着严重愤怒管理问题的家伙
A man with breathtaking anger-management issues,
一对顶级杀手  而你  好家伙
a couple of master assassins, and you, big fella,
你把他们所有人都惹毛了
you've managed to piss off every single one of them.
这就是我的计划
That was the plan.
不怎么明智
Not a great plan.
等他们来了
When they come,
他们肯定会来
and they will,
他们会让你付出代价
they'll come for you.
我有一支大军
I have an army.
我们有绿巨人
We have a Hulk.
那头野兽不是跑丢了吗
I thought the beast had wandered off.
你搞错了重点  不会有王位的
You're missing the point. There is no throne.
你是绝不可能获胜的
There is no version of this where you come out on top.
或许你有军队要来  或许我们抵挡不了
Maybe your army comes and maybe it's too much for us,
但一切都会算在你头上
but it's all on you.
因为如果我们保护不了地球
Because if we can't protect the Earth,
你就等着我们来复仇吧
you can be damn well sure we'll avenge it.
要是他们忙着对付你
How will your friends have time for me
哪还有时间来战我
when they are so busy fighting you?
以前都可以的
This usually works.
性能失常什么的也算常见了
Well, performance issues, it's not uncommon.
五个男人就有一个...
One out of five...
贾维斯  可以了
Jarvis, anytime now.
你们都会败在我脚下
You will all fall before me.
启动
Deploy!
快启动
你还惹毛了一个人
And there's one other person you pissed off.
他的名字叫菲尔
His name was Phil.
好吧
Right.
大军来了
Army.
洛基
Loki!
关掉宇宙魔方  不然我就毁了它
Turn off the Tesseract, or I'll destroy it.
你毁不掉
You can't.
你无法阻止了
There is no stopping it.
现在只有
There is only
战争
the war.
那就来吧
So be it.
斯塔克  我们在你3点钟方向  航向东北
Stark, we're on your three, headed northeast.
什么  你们去买外卖了吗
What? Did you stop for drive-through?
去帕克大街  我引他们过去给你们当靶子
Swing up Park. I'm going to lay them out for you.
先生  有更多敌人
Sir, we have more incoming.
好吧  我们去会会他们
Fine. Let's keep them occupied.
-小娜  -我看见他了
- Nat? - I see him.
我们得到上面去
We got to get back up there.
斯塔克  你看见这东西了吗
Stark, are you seeing this?
看见了  但还在消化中
Seeing. Still working on believing.
班纳出现了吗
Where's Banner? Has he shown up yet?
班纳
Banner?
他到了就告诉我
Just keep me posted.
贾维斯  找出它的弱点
Jarvis, find me a soft spot.
你自己看看
Look at this!
看看这一切
Look around you!
你以为你称了王  疯狂会就此结束吗
You think this madness will end with your rule?
太迟了
It's too late.
想阻止也来不及了
It's too late to stop it.
不  只要我们一起就可以
No. We can, together.
太天真了
Sentiment.
有平民被困在里面了
We've got civilians still trapped up here.
洛基
Loki.
他们在下面只有挨打的份
They're fish in a barrel down there.
这边有我们  没问题  你去吧
We got this. It's good. Go.
你能挡住他们吗
Do you think you can hold them off?
队长
Captain,
我非常乐意
it would be my genuine pleasure.
这让我想到了布达佩斯那次
Just like Budapest all over again.
我们对布达佩斯的回忆太不同了
You and I remember Budapest very differently.
集结国民警卫队需要一小时
It's going to be an hour before they can scramble the National Guard.
国民警卫队
National Guard?
军队知道这里发生了什么吗
Does the army know what's happening here?
我们知道吗
Do we?
派人到这些大楼里去
You need men in these buildings.
楼里的人逃跑的时候
There are people inside and they're going to be running
会被火力波及到
right into the line of fire.
要带他们走地下室或是地铁
You take them to the basements or through the subway.
别让他们到街上来
You keep them off the streets.
封锁这里到39大街
I need a perimeter as far back as 39th.
我凭什么听你指挥
Why the hell should I take orders from you?
派人到这些大楼里去
I need men in those buildings.
把人往地下带  别到街上来
Lead the people down and away from the streets.
封锁这里到39大街
We're going to set up a perimeter all the way down to 39th Street.
好吧  它盯上我们了
Well, we got its attention.
接下去怎么办
What the hell was step two?
上面怎么样了
What's the story upstairs?
包围魔方的能量无法穿透
The power surrounding the Cube is impenetrable.
托尔说得对  我们得先对付这些怪物
Thor's right. We got to deal with these guys.
-怎么对付  -齐心协力
- How do we do this? - As a team.
我和洛基还有帐要算
I have unfinished business with Loki.
是吗  排个号吧
Yeah? Well, get in line.
把力气省下来
Save it.
洛基会集中兵力对付我们
Loki's going to keep this fight focused on us,
而我们正要他这样
and that's what we need.
没有他的控制  它们会群魔无首
Without him, these things could run wild.
斯塔克在上面  他会需要我们...
We got Stark up top. He's going to need us to...
那个  看起来真恐怖
So, this all seems horrible.
我见过更恐怖的
I've seen worse.
抱歉
Sorry.
没关系  我们或许需要一点恐怖
No, we could use a little worse.
-斯塔克  他来了  -班纳吗
- Stark, we got him. - Banner?
被你说中了
Just like you said.
让他武装起来  我这就把好戏拉过去
Then tell him to suit up. I'm bringing the party to you.
我不觉得这是什么好戏
I don't see how that's a party.
班纳博士
Dr Banner.
现在你最好生气起来了
Now might be a really good time for you to get angry.
这就是我的诀窍  队长
That's my secret, Captain.
我一直在生气
I'm always angry.
撑住
Hold on!
都派出来
Send the rest.
快看
Guys.
下命令吧  队长
Call it, Captain.
好  都听好了
All right, listen up.
在关掉传送门之前  想办法控制局面
Until we can close that portal, our priority is containment.
巴顿  我要你到那个屋顶上去
Barton, I want you on that roof.
观察战场  报告敌军的动向
Eyes on everything. Call out patterns and strays.
斯塔克  你守住封锁线
Stark, you got the perimeter.
不要让这些怪物跑出三个街区
Anything gets more than three blocks out,
挡不回去的直接轰成渣
you turn it back or you turn it to ash.
-送我一程好吗  -好
- Can you give me a lift? - Right.
《魔戒》里擅长弓箭的精灵
抓紧了  莱戈拉斯
Better clench up, Legolas.
托尔  你得想办法堵上传送门
Thor, you got to try and bottleneck that portal.
拖慢它们的速度
Slow them down.
你召唤闪电  劈死这群怪物
You got the lightning. Light the bastards up.
你和我  我们守住地面
You and me, we stay here on the ground.
牵制兵力
We keep the fighting here.
绿巨人
And Hulk...
使劲砸
Smash.
长官
Sir.
理事会在线上了
The Council is on.
斯塔克  你后面跟了不少飞虫
Stark, you got a lot of strays sniffing your tail.
我是不想让它们到街上去
I'm just trying to keep them off the streets.
他们拐起弯来差劲得很
Well, they can't bank worth a damn.
找个死角
So find a tight corner.
收到
I will roger that.
真烦人
Oh, boy.
指挥得好
Nice call.
还有什么
What else you got?
托尔在6大街跟一支飞行队干起来了
Thor is taking on a squadron down on Sixth.
他居然不带我玩
And he didn't invite me.
队长  如果不关上传送门
Captain, none of this is going to mean a damn thing
我们怎么打都是徒劳
if we don't close that portal.
最强的武器都穿不透它
Our biggest guns couldn't touch it.
也许是选的武器不对
Well, maybe it's not about guns.
你上去得搭个便车
If you want to get up there, you're going to need a ride.
我有车搭
I got a ride.
不过你得推我一把
I could use a boost, though.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
嗯  肯定很有趣
Yeah. It's gonna be fun.
转弯  快转弯
Okay, turn, turn.
收住  收住
Less! Less!
队长  过麦迪逊大街的42街银行
Captain, the bank on 42nd past Madison.
有很多平民被敌人困在里面
They've cornered a lot of civilians in there.
我这就去
I'm on it.
大家让开
Everyone! Clear out!
弗瑞局长
Director Fury,
理事会已经做出决定
the Council has made a decision.
这我知道了
I recognise the Council has made a decision.
但鉴于这个决定蠢到家了
But given that it's a stupid-ass decision,
我决定无视
I have elected to ignore it.
局长  你们比我们的潜艇离得都近
Director, you're closer than any of our subs.
立刻派出战机
You scramble that jet...
那可是曼哈顿岛  理事
That is the island of Manhattan, Councilman.
除非我的队伍确实撑不住了
Until I'm certain my team can't hold it,
不然我不会下令对平民实施核打击
I will not order a nuclear strike against a civilian population.
如果不在这里挡住他们  那就无法挽回了
If we don't hold them here, we lose everything.
如果投了核弹  那才真叫无法挽回
If I send that bird out, we already have.
是你啊
You.
鹰眼
Hawkeye!
小娜  你干什么呢
Nat, what are you doing?
帮下忙
A little help?
放着我来
I got him.
够了
Enough!
你们都算什么东西
You are, all of you, beneath me!
我可是神  你这蠢货
I am a god, you dull creature.
你休想欺辱我  你这...
And I will not be bullied by...
弱爆了的神
Puny god.
权杖
The sceptre...
博士
Doctor.
洛基的权杖  它的能量
Loki's sceptre. The energy.
宇宙魔方无人能敌
The Tesseract can't fight,
但它抵挡不了来自身的攻击
but you can't protect against yourself.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你不知道自己在做什么
You didn't know what you were doing.
事实上  我知道
Actually, I think I did.
我装了一个可以切断能量源的保险装置
I built in a safety to cut their power source.
洛基的权杖
Loki's sceptre.
或许能关闭传送门
It may be able to close the portal.
它就在那里
And I'm looking right at it.
先生  我们剩下的能量不足以穿透它的外壳
Sir, we will lose power before we penetrate that shell.
《圣经》中的故事  约拿被大鱼吞下肚
贾维斯  你听过约拿的故事吗
Jarvis, you ever hear the tale of Jonah?
我不建议你学他
I wouldn't consider him a role model.
弗瑞局长已被解除指挥权
Director Fury is no longer in command.
代行命令  7A11
Override order 7-Alpha-1-1.
7A11命令确认  可以起飞
7-Alpha-1-1, confirmed. We're go for takeoff.
长官  有架战机起飞了
Sir, we have a bird in motion!
甲板人员注意  有架战机擅自起飞
Anyone on the deck, we have a rogue bird.
必须马上阻止
We need to shut it down!
重复  起飞未经许可
Repeat, takeoff is not authorised.
斯塔克  你听见了吗
Stark, do you hear me?
有一枚导弹朝曼哈顿去了
You have a missile headed straight for the city.
还有多久
How long?
最多三分钟
Three minutes, max.
它的核弹能将市中心夷为平地
The payload will wipe out Midtown.
贾维斯  将余下动力全部输至推进器
Jarvis, put everything we got into the thrusters.
输完了
I just did.
核弹已发射
Package is sent.
爆炸倒计时  2分30秒
Detonation in 2 minutes, 30 seconds, mark.
准备好再战一轮了吗
Are you ready for another bout?
怎么  你犯困了吗
What, are you getting sleepy?
对准顶部
Right at the crown!
我能关掉它
I can close it.
你们听见了吗
Can anybody copy?
我能关掉传送门
I can shut the portal down.
-快关  -别关  等等
- Do it! - No, wait.
斯塔克  敌人还在不断涌进来
Stark, these things are still coming.
有枚核弹飞过来了
I got a nuke coming in.
一分钟内就会爆炸
It's gonna blow in less than a minute.
而我刚好知道该把它送去哪
And I know just where to put it.
斯塔克  你的能量不够回来了
Stark, you know that's a one-way trip.
留着能量转弯吧  老贾
Save the rest for the turn, J.
先生  要我联系波茨小姐吗
Sir, shall I try Miss Potts?
好的
Might as well.
纽约街道沦为战场
The streets of New York City have become a battleground.
曼哈顿市中心遭袭
军队已到现场对抗敌人
The Army is here trying to contain the violence
但显然力不从心
but clearly, it is outmatched.
我得承认  我干这行这么多年
And I have to say, in all my years of reporting,
这样的事是闻所未闻
I have never seen anything like this.
我们对这支队伍知之甚少
We have limited information on the team
但我们知道亿万富翁托尼·斯塔克  即钢铁侠
but we do know that billionaire Tony Stark's Iron Man...
先生  波茨小姐...
Sir, Miss Potts...
呼叫失败
快点  斯塔克
Come on, Stark.
关上吧
Close it.
真有你的
Son of a gun.
他没有减速
He's not slowing down.
他还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
我去
What the hell?
怎么回事
What just happened?
刚刚没人亲我吧
Please tell me nobody kissed me.
我们赢了
We won.
太好了
All right, yay!
万岁  干得好  伙计们
Hurray. Good job, guys.
明天别上班了  给自己放假一天
Let's just not come in tomorrow. Let's just take a day.
你们吃过土耳其烤肉吗
Have you ever tried shawarma?
离这两条街外有家土耳其烤肉店
There's a shawarma joint about two blocks from here.
其实我没吃过  但我想尝尝
I don't know what it is, but I want to try it.
还没结束呢
We're not finished yet.
那就回头再去
And then shawarma after.
如果你们不介意
If it's all the same to you,
我现在想来一杯
I'll have that drink now.
尽管城市饱受摧残
Despite the devastation
在这起已证实为外星入侵的袭击事件中
of what has been confirmed as an extraterrestrial attack,
这支名为复仇者联盟小队的英雄壮举
the extraordinary heroics of the group known as the Avengers
对很多人来说不仅是安慰  更值得庆祝
has been to many a cause not only for comfort, but for celebration.
知道他们的存在真是太好了
It's just really great knowing they're out there.
有人在守护着我们
That someone is watching over us.
我爱你  托尔
I love you, Thor!
这些家伙就...
And then these guys were like...
到处都在爆炸
And then the air goes...
然后那个绿色的家伙就...
And this green guy walks up and he goes...
说不清
I don't know.
这些家伙的存在让我觉得不安全
I don't exactly feel safer with those things out there.
我就是有种被蒙在鼓里的感觉
It just seems that there's a lot they're not telling us.
纽约有超级英雄  少来了
Superheroes in New York? Give me a break.
这些所谓的英雄
These so-called "Heroes"
谢谢你们  复仇者联盟
必须为城市的损毁负责
have to be held responsible for the destruction done to this city.
他们打完了仗  都跑哪去了
This was their fight. Where are they now?
人们对复仇者联盟充满好奇
Tough questions are being asked about the Avengers themselves.
但他们就像当时突然出现一样地突然消失了
Their sudden appearance and equally sudden disappearance...
怎么  这事反倒怪在他们头上吗
What, this is all somehow their fault?
美国队长是我的救命恩人
Captain America saved my life.
不管他在哪里  不管他们都身处何方
Wherever he is, and wherever any of them are,
我只想
I would just...
我只想说声谢谢
I would want to say thank you.
复仇者们都去哪了
Where are the Avengers?
我暂时没有追查他们的行踪
I'm not currently tracking their whereabouts.
在我看来他们有权休假
I'd say they've earned a leave of absence.
宇宙魔方呢
And the Tesseract?
魔方已经回到了它该去的地方
The Tesseract is where it belongs.
远离我们
Out of our reach.
你无权做这种决定
That's not your call.
决定不是我做的
I didn't make it.
做这个决定的是神  我没有争辩
I just didn't argue with the god that did.
你就这么让他带走了魔方
So, you let him take it
还有该为他的罪行受到制裁的战犯洛基
and the war criminal, Loki, who should be answering for his crime.
我想他会受到制裁的
I think he will be.
我看你没意识到你这么做的后果
I don't think you understand what you've started,
就这么让复仇者们回到社会上
letting the Avengers loose on this world.
他们都是危险人物
They're dangerous.
确实  他们的威名不仅传遍天下
They surely are, and the whole world knows it.
更声振寰宇
Every world knows it.
这不正是我们的目的吗
Was that the point of all this?
一个宣言
A statement?
一个保证
A promise.
长官  之后要怎么办
Sir, how does it work now?
他们都各走各的了
They've gone their separate ways.
有的人还去了很远的地方
Some, pretty extremely far.
再遇到这种情况
If we get into a situation like this again,
我们该怎么办
what happens then?
他们还会回来
They'll come back.
你真的确定吗
Are you really sure about that?
是的
I am.
为什么
Why?
因为我们需要他们回来
Because we'll need them to.
人类
Humans.
并不像他说的那样懦弱卑微
They are not the cowering wretches we were promised.
他们坚守家园
They stand.
难以驾驭  不能被统治
They are unruly, and therefore cannot be ruled.
与他们为敌
To challenge them
无异于求死
is to court death.